Let's see, that's what I received on
a ver eso es lo que me ha llegado
the very same day, there is the
justamente lo mismo día ahí está el
ruling of the sentence, but in the ruling of the
fallo de la sentencia pero en fallo de
sentence to condemn, that is, condemned,
Sentencia para condenar o sea condenado
that for me is the most essential, no, but there will
eso para mí lo más esencial no pero que
be much more in the pages obviously, but
habrá mucho más en páginas obvio pero
let's read only the most
vamos a leer solamente la página más
important page, how they condemn and all that,
importante Cómo condenan y todo eso
so I'm going to do that, I'm going to
entonces voy a hacer eso que yo voy a
read the ruling as it is in Thai,
leer tal como está el fallo en tailandés
and then José will explain in Spanish, so
y luego José explicará en español así
I'll read it in Andalusian, if you want,
que cl yo lo leo en andaluz si queréis
I'll take it and say, listen to me, Daniel,
yo cojo y digo escúchame Daniel
an eternity
una eternidad más
later, that is what is written exactly, that is what Daniel Sanch
tarde eso es lo que está escrito tal
heard.
cual eso es lo que escuchó Daniel sanch
Then his fixer arrived and translated it for him,
Luego llegó su fixer y se lo tradujo
but Daniel Sancho, Rodolfo Sancho, and
pero Daniel Sancho Rodolfo Sancho y
everyone who was there, what
todos los que estaban allí lo que
they heard was that, and he remained the same,
escucharon fue eso y se quedó igual
I imagine he remained the same until his
imagino que se quedó Igual hasta que su
fixer told him the following: the court
fixer le dijo lo siguiente el tribunal
of the province of Cosam Very informs
de la provincia de cosam muy informa
about criminal case number
sobre el caso penal número
between the prosecutor of the province of
566 entre el fiscal de la provincia de
Cosam Very as plaintiff and Mr.
cosam muy como demandante y el señor
Daniel Jerónimo Sancho Bronchalo as
Daniel Jerónimo Sancho bronchalo como
accused, the hearing for the reading of
acusado la audiencia para la lectura de
the sentence  It was held today,
la sentencia se llevó a cabo hoy 29 de
August 29, 2023, at 10:24 a.m. Ferrana
agosto de 2023 a las 10 horas 24 ferrana
Jos 2024. Sorry, yes, thank you. At
Jos 2024 perdón sí gracias a las 10
10:00 a.m., the court issued a sentence
horas el tribunal dictó sentencia
declaring the accused guilty according to the
declarando al acusado culpable según el
penal code, articles 188, 199, and
código penal artículo 188 199 y
289. The accused's actions
289 las acciones de del acusado
constitute several different crimes,
constituyen varios delitos diferentes
for which reason a sentence will be imposed for
por lo que se le impondrá una pena por
each of them according to article
cada uno de ellos de acuerdo al artículo
91 of the penal code. For concealing,
91 del código penal por ocultar
transferring, or destroying a corpse or part
trasladar o destruir un cadáver o parte
of a corpse, he is sentenced to 4 months in
de un cadáver con una pena de 4 meses de
prison. For premeditated homicide, he is
prisión por homicidio premeditado se le
sentenced to the death penalty. For damaging,
condena a la pena de muerte y por dañar
destroying, or appropriating
o destruir o apropiarse de documentos de
another person's documents, he is sentenced to 2
otra persona se le impone una pena de 2
years in prison. The accused pleaded
años de prisión el acusado Se declaró
guilty to the crime of concealing, transferring, or
culpable del delito de ocultar traslad o
destroying a corpse or part of a
destruir un cadáver o parte de un
corpse, which is considered an extenuating circumstance,
cadáver lo que se considera un atenuante
for which reason the sentence is reduced by half,
por lo que se reduce la pena a la mitad
leaving it at two months in prison.
quedando en dos meses de prisión en
Regarding the charge of
cuanto a la acusación de homicidio
premeditated homicide, it is considered an extenuating circumstance and
premeditado se considera un atenuante y
the sentence is reduced to a third,
se le reduce la pena a un tercio
leaving it in life imprisonment. According to
quedando en cadena perpetua según el
article  78 of the Penal Code in
artículo 78 del Código Penal en
combination with article 52 once
combinación con el artículo 52 una vez
the court imposes the sentence of life
que el tribunal impone la pena de cadena
imprisonment, no other penalties may be added,
perpetua no se pueden sumar ninguna otra
in addition, the defendant is ordered to pay
pena además se ordena al acusado pagar
the sum of
la suma de
4,424,000 W plus interest at 5% per year
4,42 4,000 W más intereses al 5% anual
from August 2,
desde el 2 de Agosto de
2023 until payment is completed to the
2023 hasta que se complete el pago a los
joint defendants if the Ministry of
demandados conjuntos si el Ministerio de
Finance modifies the interest rate
finanzas modifica la tasa de intereses
by royal decree, the
mediante un real decreto se aplicará la
adjusted rate will be applied plus an increase of 2%
tasa ajustada más un incremento del 2%
per year but will not exceed 5% as for
anual pero no excederá el 5% en cuanto a
the plaintiff's other requests,
las otras solicitudes del demandante
joint defendants are dismissed, the
anes conjuntos se desestiman las costas
court costs in the civil part are dismissed as
judiciales en la parte civil según lo
requested by the two
solicitado por los dos
co-defendants that is what was said in
codemandados eso es lo que se dijo en
Spanish, meaning that as of
español o sea que ya desde la fecha de 2
August 2, 2023 of last year, they already have to
de Agosto 2023 de año pasado Ya ya tiene
pay interest 5% Exactly,
que pagar intereses 5% Exacto los
articles 188 are the following, I am going
artículos 188 son los siguientes lo voy
to read it that whoever causes damage, destroys,
a leer que quien cause daños destruye
hides, takes or causes to lose or render
oculte se lleve o haga perder o
useless a will or any
inutilizar un testamento o cualquier
document of another person in a way that
documento de otra persona de manera que
may cause harm to others or to the
pueda causar perjuicio a otros o a la
society will be punished with a
sociedad será castigado con una pena de
prison sentence of up to 5 years and a fine of
prisión de hasta 5 años y una multa de
up to 100,000 W article 199 these
hasta 100,000 W el artículo 199 estos
are the three articles for which he has been
son los tres artículos por los que se le
convicted the penal code establishes
ha condenado el código penal Establece
that whoever hides transfers or
que quien oculte esconda transfiera o
destroys a corpse or part of the corpse
destruya un cadáver o parte del cadáver
to cover up the birth death or
para encubrir el nacimiento la muerte o
the cause of death will be punished with
la causa de la muerte será castigado con
a prison sentence of up to one year or a
una pena de prisión de hasta un año o
fine of up to 1000 W with or both
una multa de hasta 1000 W con o ambas
penalties and article 289 of the penal code
penas y el artículo 289 del Código Penal
is an article of the penal code that
es un artículo de Código Penal que
establishes the following whoever kills a
establece lo siguiente quien mate a un
parent an official acting in
progenitor a un funcionario que actúe en
the exercise of his functions or for
el ejercicio de sus funciones o por
reasons connected with the exercise of
motivos relacionados con el ejercicio de
his functions kills an assistant of an
sus funciones mate a un asistente de un
official at the time when an
funcionario en el momento en el que un
official is acting in the exercise of his
funcionario actúe en el ejercicio de sus
functions or for reasons connected with
funciones o por motivos relacionadas con
the assistance that that person has given to the
la ayuda que esta persona haya brindado
official mediating kills another
al funcionario mediando mate a otra
person with premeditation kills another
persona con premeditación mate a otra
person tortures or commits acts of
persona torturo o cometiendo actos de
cruelty kills another person to
crueldad mate a otra persona para
prepare or facilitate the commission of another
preparar o facilitar la comisión de otro
crime or kills another  person to
delitro o mate a otra persona para
obtain or retain benefits derived
obtener o retener beneficios derivados
from the commission of another crime in order to
de la comisión de otro delito con el fin
cover up his own offense or to
de encubrir su propia infracción o para
avoid criminal liability for
evitar la responsabilidad penal por
other crimes that he has committed will be
otros delitos que haya cometido será
punished with the death penalty. Those are
castigado con la pena de muerte Esos son
the three articles with which he has been
los tres artículos con los que se le ha
sentenced but also very important
condenado a pero también muy importante
is a small detail that they are being tried with the
es un poco detalle que están juzgado con
death penalty, that is, the capital penalty, it is
pena de muerte o sea pena capital
only commuted to life imprisonment
solamente es conmutado carena perpetua
but it has been sentenced as a capital penalty
pero la ha condenado como pena capital
therefore the Ritaa family is very
por lo tanto la familia ritaa muy
satisfied firstly by the
satisfecha primer lugar por la califica
legal qualification of the facts as he said
jurídica de los hechos como bien decía
premeditated murder he planned to
asesinato con premeditación planeó
end the life of Edwin Arrieta
acabar con la vida de Edwin Arrieta en
secondly by what is understood
segundo lugar por lo que se entiende
as murder Daniel Sancho ended
Como asesinato Daniel Sancho acabó con
the life of Edwin without him being
la vida de Edwin sin que é mismo se
able to defend himself Daniel Sancho
pudiera defender Daniel Sancho le
punched him in the head Daniel
propina un puñetazo en la cabeza Daniel
Sancho is a martial arts practitioner Edwin
Sancho es practica artes marciales Edwin
could not defend himself he fell to the ground
no se pudo defender cayó al suelo
convulsing Daniel Sancho finishes him off and
convulsionando lo remata Daniel Sancho y
treats him like an animal dismembered and
lo trata como un animal descuartizo y
throwing him into the sea and the garbage can
tirándolo al mar y al cubo de basura
your son has been found guilty
vuestro hijo ha sido declarado culpable
of premeditated murder
de asesinato con premeditación
dismemberment concealment of
descuartizamiento ocultación de
documents  or destruction has been accused
documentos o destrucción ha sido acusado
of all of that by a Thai court it doesn't matter
de todo eso por un tribunal tailandés da
if human rights in St.
igual que los derechos humanos de San
Petersburg or Madrid say otherwise he has
Petersburgo o de Madrid digan otra cosa
been accused in Thailand he has been
ha sido acusado en Tailandia ha sido
convicted in Thailand and you have to
condenado en Tailandia y tenéis que
work with Thailand not with some guy with a
trabajar con Tailandia no con un tío con
mustache and a lady who walks around on
bigote y una señora que se pasea por las
television telling people that she is
televisiones diciéndole a la gente que
going to sue and Rodolfo I say this
le va a poner demandas y Rodolfo lo digo
from the heart if what we want are
de corazón si lo que queremos son series
television series and [ __ ] then Okay great
de televisión y gilipolleces pues Vale
that's great but here you
cojonudo eso va cojonudo pero aquí no
are not neither strong nor stronger you cry
eres Ni fuerte ni no más fuerte lloras
like no one else like we have all cried
como el que más como todos hemos llorado
and like we all will cry you are not a
y como todos lloraremos no eres Ni un
macho nor a superman you are a guy who
macho ni un superhombre eres un tío que
happened to have a son who has killed
le ha tocado tener un hijo que ha matado
another person premeditatedly and
a otra persona premeditadamente y lo ha
dismembered him and there is no need to be
descuartizado y no hay que tener
ashamed there is no need to act like a pimp
vergüenza tampoco hay que ir de chulo
because you have been such a pain in the
por la vida porque habéis tocado tanto
ass both the lawyers and
los los tanto los abogados como
the press that everything can be seen here for
la prensa que aquí se ve todo para
us this life sentence is very important
nosotros es muy importante esta cadena
on the one hand I think it will
perpetua por un lado creo que va a
serve as a time for
servir de un tiempo para reflexionar a
Daniel Sancho to reflect on what he has done he has
Daniel Sancho de lo que ha hecho ha
come to defend and  to say that Daniel
venido a defender y a referir que Daniel
Sancho I think lives a
Sancho creo que vive una realidad
different reality than ours I am convinced
distinta a la nuestra estoy convencido
that if he is asked today about how I know if they are
que si se le pregunta hoy sobre cómo se
going to say that he feels fine because that is the case
si van a decir que se siente bien porque
well he says that he was crying uh that he
es así bueno dice que estaba llorando eh
is crying that he is very depressed
que est llorando que está muy decaído
that he has asked for forgiveness several times
que ha pedido Perdón varias veces
dear I do not know where this
querido Yo no sé de dónde viene esa
information comes from in the first place because as you
información en primer lugar porque como
have said the lawyers have gone to
bien habéis dicho los abogados han ido a
Thailand to do the Asian Walk
Tailandia a hacer el Paseo asiático
because they could not enter the courtroom
porque no han podido entrar en la sala
this could come to a journalist who
esto puede venir a un periodista que que
was inside the court or I do not know
estuviera dentro de la corte o no sé
where this information comes from I do not know if what
dónde viene esta información no sé si lo
they are trying to do now is to empathize with the
que intentan es ahora empatizar con la
audience what is clear to me is that to
audiencia lo que tengo claro es que a
this
día de hoy a la familia Rita no se le ha
day the Rita family has not been asked for forgiveness for having killed Edwin at any time and I hope hopefully this sentence we are not seeking revenge will serve so that Daniel Sancho assimilates the consequences of the profound evil that he committed and God willing I am a jurist who practices law in
soy un jurista que ejerce la abogacía en
Spain we believe in reintegration we believe
España creemos en la reinserción creemos
in resocialization we believe in
en la resocialización creemos en las
second chances I hope this
segundas oportunidades Ojalá esta
second chance comes to Daniel
segunda oportunidad le llega a Daniel
either  much less, I mean, we're
tampoco por mucho menos o sea estamos
talking about two months in which
hablando de dos meses en lo que se queda
the issue of dismemberment remains, but it is also
el tema del descuartizamiento pero es
cooking, it has also lowered everything
cocimiento también la ha rebajado todo
because they recognize her and then also cu
porque la reconocen y luego tamb cu
months are not normally more what
meses tampoco normalmente son más lo que
happens is that in the video of reconstruction
pasa que que en vídeo de reconstrucción
of the events since I think day 5 or day
de los hechos desde creo que día 5 o día
6 which was reconstruction of the events
6 que fue reconstrucción de los hechos
that is what has saved his life because
eso es lo que ha salvado su vida porque
he already had the death sentence, the sentence
él ya tenía la condena de muerte la pena
captain, for now, we'll go for a long
capitán desde hace ya vamos desde hacen
time now because it is very clear but to
ya tiempo porque está clarísimo pero an
have those videos, those videos of
tener esos vídeos esos vídeos de
reconstruction of the events as
reconstrucción de los hechos como
collaborating, they are telling him where the
colaborando le están diciendo dónde
body is, how was it in the murder
están cadáver Cómo fue en asesinato en
where he hit, I mean, it means that they
dónde golpeo o sea quiere decir que
are collaborating with the police in the
están colaborando a la policía de la
investigation, so it was that and who
investigación entonces fue eso y quién
told him that he had to collaborate, all
le dijo lo que tenía que colaborar todo
that was with Ana, of course, it was with Ana who
eso fue con aná claro fue con aná que lo
said it. That is why what surprised me, they
dijo Por eso lo que yo me extrañaba me
make me laugh when the defense came out and
hacen risa cuando la defensa ha salido y
said that the president of the court,
diciendo que presidente de de la corte
as if congratulating Daniel
como dando las felicitaciones a Daniel
because the defense is doing great, the
porque la defensa está hecho genial la
defense, what he prefers is the defense
defensa lo que él prefiere es la defensa
from the beginning that was J, not that the
de al principio que fue J no que la
defense was so disastrous, what there is
defensa tan desastrosa lo que hay
currently of them In
actualmente de ellos En el video de
Tomorrow I'll put that cl no in which he
Mañana pongo yo ese cl no en el que él
says that he is happy not because the
dice que está contento no porque la
defense has done a very good job
defensa ha hecho muy buen trabajo A
Despite this Marco Garcia Montees at the
pesar de esto marco García montees en la
door of the court after the reading of the
puerta del juzgado tras la lectura del
ruling had the balls to celebrate
fallo tuvo los cojon de celebrarlo
because he says that the court has highlighted
porque dice que el tribunal ha destacado
that it is a life sentence instead of a
que es una cadena perpetua en vez de una
death penalty because of the good work that
pena de muerte por el buen trabajo que
the defense has done what I have said is
ha hecho la defensa lo que he dicho es
that the president has translated for us
que el presidente se nos ha traducido
that he said that it is a life sentence
que ha dicho que es cadena perpetua
because a good job has been done
porque se ha hecho un buen trabajo
defense and the pras well well well
defensa y las pras bueno bueno bueno
Chona
Chona
I said I nailed it I nailed it well in fact he has not
dije lo clavé lo clavé bueno de hecho no
only said that at the door of the
solamente ha dicho eso en la puerta del
court he also said that Daniel Sancho
juzgado también dijo que Daniel Sancho
was not declared convicted but a
no fue declarado condenado sino preso
preventive prisoner the president has told
preventivo el presidente le ha dicho a
Daniel that he is not a convicted prisoner that
Daniel que él no es preso condenado que
he is a preventive prisoner and that he has the
él es preso preventivo y que tiene
right to resources So nothing family
derecho a recursos Así que nada familia
I will not be the one to contradict
no seré yo quien le lleve la contraria a
a professional like this Daniel Sancho
un profesional como este Daniel Sancho
is not convicted okay he is
no está condenado vale está condenado
preventively sentenced in the meantime just in case
preventivamente de mientras por si acaso
for what can happen Although I
por lo que puede pasar Aunque
sincerely have my doubts that in
sinceramente tengo mi dudas de que en
a sentence they have highlighted the work of
una sentencia hayan destacado el trabajo
the lawyer and less of a
del abogado y menos de un abogado
Spanish lawyer who  In fact, the one who was practicing in the
español que en verdad no ejerce en el
case is not the one who was practicing in the case, as I
caso el que ejercía en el caso como ya
was already explaining to you in the
os estuve explicando en los vídeos
previous videos, it is a professional that they took on
anteriores es uno de oficio que cogieron
in order to be able to handle it and to lend itself to
para poder manejarlo y que se prestase a
all the nonsense that
todas las tonterías que se le ocurrieran
García Montes could come up with. But sincerely, no, the
a García Montes Pero sinceramente no el
objective that this firm had was not a
objetivo que tenía este bufete no era el
life sentence. The objective that
de una cadena perpetua el objetivo que
this firm had, therefore, has not
tenía este bufete por lo tanto no ha
been a triumph on their part but a
sido un triunfo por su parte sino un
failure, it was an acquittal. We
fracaso era el de la absolución Nosotros
have always put on the table
siempre hemos puesto encima de la mesa
that we are going for Daniel's solution.
que vamos a por la solución de Daniel
Regarding the two charges that he
Respecto a los dos cargos que él se
pleads innocent from the first day, not in the
declara inocente de primer día no en la
current defense, which has made everything
defensa actual que la ha hecho todo
disastrous, which has clearly been demonstrated. Put
desastroso que ha demostrado clar Pon
a lot of click that they are
mucho cli que ellos lo que están
always fighting for the solution, not for life
peleando siempre por la solución no por
imprisonment. When it says 2566
la cadena perpetua cuando pone 2566
because it is the Buddhist year, yes, we are
porque es el año budista sí estamos
currently in
ahora actualmente en
267, Exactly 66, 2023, for example, here it says
267 Exacto 66 2023 por ejemplo aquí pone
August 2, 2566 Because they were and
2 de Agosto de 2566 Porque eran y
Buddhists, But this is actually 2023,
budistas Pero esto en realidad es 2023
there also when they put in case
ahí también en cuando ponen en caso
penalty number
penal número
118/2 that means that it is 11 that the
118/2 esa quiere decir que es 11 que el
11th 8th is the month of August Okay and var 202
día 11 8 es mes de agosto Vale y var 202
Exactly when it says that it is not added of
Exacto cuando dice que no se le suma
course once sentenced to life
claro una vez condenado a cadena
imprisonment then the rest of the sentence is not added
perpetua pues no se suma el resto de la
because we are talking about
pena porque estamos hablando del
infinity we are not talking about a
infinito no estamos hablando de una
life sentence but in the case that
cadena perpetua pero en el caso de que
the life sentence is reduced to
se vaya rebajando la cadena perpetua a
50 years what happens with the other
los 50 años qué pasa con las otras
sentences does not have to serve all of them is that
condenas no tiene que cumplir todos es
by part not included eh that go in
que por parte no incluido eh eso van en
different Or in other words he has to
diferentes O sea que en tiene que
serve all the cu months in a year
cumplir todos los cu meses los en un año
and a half of 2 years all that he has to serve that they are
y pico de 2 años todo eso tiene que
not going to give it away if they
cumplir eso no lo van a regalar si
get him to reduce the
consigue que le rebajen la cadena
life sentence to 50 years it is 50 years plus the
perpetua a 50 años son 50 años más los
two years years and cu months no well he says no
dos años años y cu meses no bueno dice
no because he says that as I understand it
que no no porque dice que según entiendo
uh here it says that since he is sentenced to life
yo eh aquí pone que al estar condenado a
imprisonment
cadena perpetua ya no se le puede sumar
the rest of the sentences cannot be added or in other words the calculation
el resto de penas o sea el cómputo
gl remains in each life cu excuse me of
gl queda en cad perpetua cu perdone
course it is as if with a capital sentence
claro es como si te con una pena capital
what else will they give you  to add if they are going to
que más te van a sumar si ya te van a
kill you I mean not being infinite the line
matar O sea no estando infinito la línea
of Thailand when they put the death penalty on him
de Tailandia cuando ellos le pongan pena
and then in capital punishment with
capital y luego en pena capital con
mutated But it means that he has
mutado Pero quiere decir que la ha
sentenced him to death is that they
condenado pena capitán es que ellos
always focus on that saying that he
siempre enfocan eso que diciendo que no
is not sentenced to life imprisonment
es condenado a cariana perpetua
sentenced to death captain Therefore they are
condenado pena capitán Por lo cual la
going to treat her as a prisoner with the
van a catar como un preso con pena
death penalty Hey, we have to keep one
capital Oye hay que tener en cuenta una
thing in mind, eh, we are talking about the
cosa eh que estamos hablando de que los
interest being 106,000 5% Eh yes
intereses son de 106000 El 5% Eh sí el
next year next year they
año que viene el año que viene la
will have to pay 2% more included in that year C you don't pay until 8 years from now We are talking about 40 thousand more turkeys eh so be careful with that eh because here The longer you take to pay each
aquí no Cuanto más tardes en pagar cada
year it's 5,000 and some euros more and we will
año son 5000 y pico de euros más y nos
be there until they pay us everything, we won't be there
andr hasta que nos paguen todo no andr
the costs have Cars each year are 5,000
los cuestes tien Cars cada año son 5000
and some euros more which
y pico de euros más que se va
increases the economic amount
incrementando la cuantía economica por
therefore if you don't pay until you are not
lo tanto si no pagas hasta que no te
going to come  that are 8 years well we
vayas a venir que son 8 años pues
can calmly talk about 40 something
podemos hablar tranquilamente de 40
euros more no no you can't stay
tantos euros más no no se puede quedado
there for years more until they pay the
allí años más hasta que no paguen el
last cent they are not going to get out of
último centavo no la van a salir de
Thailand I'm not even dreaming I mean the thing is pay
Tailandia ni sueño o sea la cosa es paga
now just in case because for now
ya por si acaso porque ya de momento
you have to pay for now you have to
tienes que pagar de momento tienes que
pay 5000 more because from 2023 they
pagar 5000 más ya porque desde 2023
start counting interest So
empiezan a contar intereses O sea que
I think there is money Because with everything
dinero yo creo que hay Porque con todo
in father that they do everything in documentary and
en padre que hacen todo en documental y
all that I think they should already
todo eso creo que debería ya van
speed things up not to
agilizando las cosas no para que
soften also with changes the prison and
suavizan también con cambio la prisión y
all that people see it and the guards
todo eso la gente lo ve y Los guardianes
know it all good that they see it Because
lo saben todos bueno que lo vean Porque
at least if they hadn't seen this
por lo menos si ellos no habí visto este
document that has been leaked
documento que se ha filtrado lo tiene
tuyupa has it at least they already know that for
tuyupa por lo menos ya saben que de
now it's not 106000 because they have to
momento no son 106000 porque tienen que
pay 5% starting in 2023 but
pagar 5% ya desde 2023 pero es que el
next year they are going to have to pay another
año que viene van a tener que pagar otro
5% in other words start paying now because it's 5000
5% o sea ir pagando ya porque son 5000
more every year eh the interest goes up
más cada año eh va subiendo intereses cl
clear clear that's why it's good to start paying
claro cl eso por eso es bueno ir pagando
from  the beginning instead of paying
desde el principio en vez de ir pagando
the witness very well very well Javi No no
la testigo muy bien muy bien Javi No no
but I would also pay because if not it
pero yo también pagaría porque si no es
is easier for everyone when they are
que es más fácil para todos en cuando
going to ask for real forgiveness they are not going to make it
van a pedir perdón real no lo van a
easy because what do you think
facilitar porque ellos qué crees que
they would run them they are going to all the
ellos los corrían la van a todos la
story left imprisoned and they know it they
historia dejada preso y lo saben ellos
have all that what each one what they do
tienen todo eso lo que cada uno lo que
In what sentence does he have And why was it
hac En qué condena tiene Y por qué fue
for has been accused and everything and then he says and what is it that they
por ha acusado y todo y luego dice y qué
fantasize like they fantasize for sure
es lo que fantan como fantan para seguro
that the account between August when he
quea cuenta los inter agosto cuando lo
killed him without knowing the sentence you already have to
mató sin saber la condena ya tienes que
go paying mat ended his life on
ir pagando a mat acabó con su vida el
August 2nd it has already generated a year of
día 2 de Agosto ya ha generado un año de
interest because it has been a year since he
intereses porque hay hace un año que lo
killed him account from August 2nd it
mató cuenta desde desde el 2 de Agosto
puts it there August 2nd of 23
te lo pone ahí 2 de agosto del 23 Por
Why Because he kills him on August 2nd when he
qué Porque lo mata el 2 de Agosto cuando
dies he has to start paying from
muente tiene que empezar a pagar desde
last year yes August here in Europe it would
el año pasado sí agosto aquí en Europa
not count of course it would count from
no se contaría claro se contaría desde
the sentence Because if
la condena Porque si
not already already but it is what I tell you it
noo ya ya ya pero es lo que te digo
would create defenselessness because how are you going to
crearía indefensión porque tú cómo vas a
know that they are going to condemn you And how much you  they are going to
saber que te van a condenar Y cuánto te
condemn And if it is going to be a
van a condenar Y si va a ser una condena
monetary sentence it is going to be a criminal sentence,
de dinero va a ser una condena penal
you know, I mean it is a little bit what I told you
sabes o sea es un poco lo que te dije
that they have been very clear from the
que ellos tienen muy claro desde el
beginning and penalty captain has it very
principio y pena capitán la tiene
clear and I think that he has been warned
clarísimo y yo creo que la ha su avisado
by in the video and so many defenses
por en el vídeo y tanta las defensa
mother m in this case it is very clear
madre m en este caso sí está clarísimo
but I understand that in all cases the
pero yo entiendo queo tod los casos el
issue of interest there can be a
tema de los intereses se puede dar un
case in which you from the first
caso en el que tú desde el primer
moment you think that there is a guilty party and
momento te pienses que hay un culpable y
suddenly the evidence shows you the
de repente las pruebas te demuestren los
opposite that it is not this okay but
contrarios que no es este vale pero de
suddenly you cannot go paying without
repente tú no puedes ir pagando sin
knowing the final result of the sentence, I
saber el resultado final de la condena o
mean I see it a little bit Thailand is like that
sea lo veo un poco Tailandia es así
already pragmatic Total does not complicate
ya pragmático Total no se complica la
life or they pay or they pay but already of course those
vida o pagan o pagan pero ya claro esas
to me the 100,000 euros seem very little
a mí los 100000 eur me parecen muy poco
money no I tell you one thing to what
dinero no yo te digo una cosa a lo que
hul Luis Garrido jul said it seems high to me
dijo hul Luis Garrido jul me parece alto
because he said that normally the
porque él dijo que normalmente las las
compensations there in Thailand
indemnizaciones allí en Tailandia se
moved around 40 50,000 euros,
movían en torno a los 40 50,000 eur o
in other words they have put  106,000 seems to me to be
sea le han puesto 106,000 me parece
within what they usually are there in
dentro de lo que son suelen ser allí en
Thailand, they claw are, it seems to me that they are 25 or
Tailandia se garra son me pare son 25 o
30,000 and with respect to compensation, is
30,000 y respecto a la indemnización se
the family satisfied with the
queda satisfecha la familia con la
amount that has been determined or will there be an
cuantía que han determinado o va a haber
appeal? Yes, we are satisfied with the
recurso sí estamos satisfechos con la
amount determined, first of all,
cuantidad determinada en primer lugar
so that the audience understands, Daniel
para que la audiencia lo entienda Daniel
Sánchez is a person without assets,
Sánchez persona sin patrimonio por lo
therefore the request for compensation was
tanto la petición de la indemnización se
based more on a formal
fundamentaba más en una cuestión formal
than a material issue. When someone has
que material Cuando alguien no tiene
nothing, nothing for nothing is nothing. However, it
nada nada por nada es nada sin embargo
is no less true that now it is said that
no es menos cierto que ahora se dice que
Daniel is going to write a book, that he is going to
Daniel va a escribir un libro que va a
make a television series. Well, it was
hacer una serie de televisión bueno era
important to impose
importante que se impusiera una
civil liability so that in his
responsabilidad civil para que en su
case, if tomorrow comes to better
caso si el día de mañana viene a mejor
fortune, it could be seized.
fortuna se le pudiera embargar por lo
Therefore, we have to assess how
tanto tenemos que entrar a valorar Cómo
the court reached its conclusion.
ha llegado el tribunal a a su conclusión
We are very satisfied with the
nos mostramos muy satisfechos con las
legal theses with the qualification of
tesis jurídicas con la calificación de
the facts and we thank the court
los hechos y agradecemos a al tribunal
of cosa mu and also the prosecution, who
de cosa mu y también a la fiscalía que
maintained at all times the premeditation,
mantuvo en todo momento la premeditación
because the ruling has been reached. And for
pues eh que el fallo haya llegado Y por
what neither that he was tortured No yes it was the
qué tampoco que se torturó No sí fue
death penalty then it was communicated to life
pena de muerte luego se comuto a cadena
imprisonment but it was the death penalty and the
perpetua pero fue pena de muerte y la
compensation I think is 25 or 30,000
indemnización creo que son 25 o 30,000
euros eh this you
eur eh este tú
25000 claw claw I tell you and
25000 garra se garra yo te digo y nos
Luis Garrido told us he didn't say it he said the
dijo Luis Garrido no lo dijo dijo las
compensations are usually very low if
indemnizaciones suelen ser muy bajas si
you gave them to the judge another thing is that the
las diste al juez otra cosa es que la
family wanted to compensate the damages And
familia haya querido resarcir el daño Y
then he pays the maximum to look good
entonces paga el máximo para quedar bien
but if the judge is the one who said the
pero si el juez es el que dicha la
compensation is usually very low let's say the
indemnización suele ser muy bajo vamos
best anyone can do better than
que lo mejor que hac cualquier mejor que
nothing 100,000 and some change better than nothing
nada 100,000 y pico mejor que nada
man I also tell you one thing 700,000
hombre tambén te digo una cosa 700,000
paying it will cost him his life 100,000
pagarlo le va a costar la vida 100,000
is another chapter of HB Ho and he pays you
es otro capitulo de HB Ho y te lo paga
said badly and soon or not I think you
dicho mal y pronto o no Yo creo que ya
can pay s well let's see we don't know if
puedes pagar s bueno a ver no sabemos si
the HBO salary is for the
el sueldo de hbo es por el paquete
complete package or is it per episode well qua
completo o es por episodio bueno qua
signs with uncle I know what do you want me to
firma con tío yo que sé quieres que te
tell you let's see  100000 is an amount that is
diga a ver 100000 es una cantidad que es
obviously affordable for these people
asequible evidentemente para esta gente
and if they are going to pay it I have no
y si lo va a pagar yo no me cabe ninguna
doubt that before spending their
duda que antes que pasarse la vida
entire life there without paying, they will get it
entera allí sin pagar eso se lo va a
and from now on
conseguir pagar y que a partir de ahora
I believe that if he has the means, he will send
yo creo que si tiene cabe mandará a
this team of lawyers to hell and forgive me for the expression
expresión a este equipo de abogados
Rodolfo Sancho listen to me listen to me,
Rodolfo Sancho escúchame escúchame que
I have been there for 7 years, stuck inside what
yo he estado 7 años ahí metido dentro de
is the house, take those lawyers,
lo que es la casa coge esos abogados
shake their hands, thank them and tell them to [ __ ]
Dales la mano d las gracias y Mándalos a
off, everything around them,
la todo lo que hay alrededor
tell him to [ __ ] off, nobody is going to get
Mándalo a la nadie va a sacar a
your son out of jail, nobody is going to
tu hijo de la cárcel nadie va a
get a parole or
conseguir una una condicional ni va a
get absolutely nothing, your son is
conseguir absolutamente nada tu hijo se
going to spend 8 or 10 years in Thailand at
va a pasar 8 o 10 años en Tailandia por
least, at least 8 or 10 years if
lo menos por lo menos 8 o 10 años si
you screw up and get to the Supreme Court,
tocáis los y llegáis al supremo
you have the possibility of being sentenced
tienes la posibilidad de que le condenen
to death, you have that possibility and
a muerte tienes esa posibilidad y
hire lawyers who do not continue saying
contrata abogados que no sigan diciendo
that if the police do this, that if the
que si la la policía esto que si las
investigations of the other one, that  look, the
pesquisas del otro que fíjate que el
judge relied on the
juez se ha fiado del informe de la
police report, and what's he going to rely on the
policía y de qué se va a fiar del
report that the plastic bags
informe de que las bolsas de plástico
were used to make raincoats for an entire
eran para hacer chubasqueros para todo
school, or on his Spanish psychiatrist?
un colegio o del psiquiatra suyo español
Say something about the team of lawyers here,
di una cosa de los Equipo de abogad aquí
the aforementioned Nilson, saying paying lawyers in
dice la dicha nilson pagar abogados en
Spain paying lawyers in Thailand, this is
España pagar abogados en Tailandia esto
crazy, but Thailand hasn't
una locura pero si Tailandia no ha
paid any, there I go, I'm going to tell you
pagado ninguna ahí voy voy voy a contar
something, first the one from Thailand ex
una cosa primero el de Tailandia de
officio and second, well, but
oficio y segundo Bueno pero pagaría
poran would pay, no, wait, wait, yes, because unan was
poran no Espera espera Sí porque unan sí
paid, but little, I don't handle the case.
se pagó pero pero poco no llevo el caso
But well, Thailand has ex officio, but it's that
Pero bueno tailanda ha en oficio pero es
then García Montes the last time he
que luego García montes en la última vez
went out with Álvaro said, I haven't
que salió con Álvaro dijo yo no he
charged a penny for this case, and also
cobrado un duro por este caso y además
the expenses here in Thailand, including
los gastos de aquí de tailand incluido
the good hom, I've paid them, that's what he
los buen hom lo he pagado yo eso es lo
said, but I don't know which one it is, yes, well,
que dijo pero la no sé cuál es sí Bueno
but you, ah, I don't know, if it were Rodolfo, I would
pero er tú ah no sé yo si fuera Rodolfo
say, get out, the t would say a world, have you
le diría sal la t diría un món te ha
paid you? Yes, I'll pay you, no, but
pagado tú si te lo pago yo no pero
listen to me, Rodolfo. Let's see if Marcos
escúchame Rodolfo A lo a ver si Marcos
gam Monte has  That said, I don't doubt it
gam Monte ha dicho eso yo no lo dudo
because why would he charge Rodolfo
porque para qué va a cobrarle a Rodolfo
if TV is going to charge 300 in the afternoon,
si va a cobrar la tele 300 por la tarde
another 300 in the morning, and I don't even know
otros 300 por la mañana y no sé ni
how many programs he's done, do you understand?
cuántos programas ha hecho me entiendes
Now, another thing is what Rodolfo can
ahora otra cosa lo que Rodolfo le puede
say to Nilson, what he can call bullfighting,
decir a nilson que le puede decir torear
is that right now I have a lot of expenses, I'll
es que ahora mismo tengo muchos gastos
give you something, he doesn't have to tell
ya te regalaré algo no tiene por decir
the truth either. So it came out for
la verdad tampoco O sea que te ha salido
free, do you believe it? Yes, I do because that
gratis tú te lo crees Yo sí porque eso
's quite common, you know that
es bastante habitual tú lo sabes que que
when there are cases, they charge for going on TV and such, okay, I
cuando hay cas cobr por ir la tele y tal
believe it, but listen to me, he has a
vale me lo creo pero escúchame tiene
lot of famous people and it's not free for
muchos famosos y no es gratis para
any of them, eh? No, and what he has, pure
ninguno eh No y lo que tiene pura de
account, any lawyer can tell, they're going to
cuenta cualquier abogado cuenta la van a
pay for it. It's that, inside, inside, the one who has
pagar Es que dentro dentro de quien más
gone to the dishes the most hasn't been him because
ha ido a los platos no ha sido él porque
when what happened with Rafael Amar happened, he got out
cuando pasó lo de Rafael amar se quitó
of the way and was there that whole week, which
del medio y estuvo toda esa semana que
was the week of the trial and everything with
fue la semana del juicio y todo con
Rafael Amaro, he wasn't aware of this
Rafael amargo no estuvo pendiente del
trial, he didn't come out talking about this
juicio de este no salió hablando de este
trial and then, man, balfagón and chipi.
juicio y luego hombre balfagón y chipi
Yes, at a given moment, the two of us, especially
Sí en un momento dado yos dos sobre todo
balfagón. It's true that he was  I was on a
balfagón Es verdad que estaba estaba en
program in the morning and in the afternoon, not
programa por la mañana y por la tarde no
balfagón, one in the morning and another
balfagón que uno por la mañana y otro
in the afternoon, the cache of a lawyer who
por la tarde el caché de un abogado que
goes on television is about 380, 400, the 800
va a televisión son unos 380 400 los 800
papers were released every day,
papetes se sacaba todos los días diarios
eh, he did three or four programs a
eh hacía tres o cuatro programas a la
week, but it has been
semana pero se ha
done and we will never know. But what
hechoo y la nunca lo sabremos Pero lo
I do not understand is what team
que yo no entiendo es qué equipo hacen
balfagón and García
balfagón y García
mones make up. Montes was the lawyer Daniel
mones Montes era el abogado Daniel
barfon and chirras, not barón and chirras, they were
barfon y chirras no barón y chirras eran
Rodolfo's lawyers and spokesperson,
los abogados de Rodolfo y portavoz
as well as criminologists who have made the
además de criminólogos que han hecho el
report. At the press conference, they said
informe en la rueda de prensa dijeron
that they belonged to the legal team. I do not know
que pertenecían al equipo jurídico no sé
what a fuss the guy made.
qué se montó un pisto el tío Se tiró un
García Monte made a mess. That seemed to him. In
chardo el García Monte aquello parecía
addition, he even compared himself to
además se comparó hasta con el equipo
Giuliani's legal team, the mayor of
jurídico de de giuliani del alcalde de
New York, that is, he said like Juliani, a
Nueva York o sea decía como juliani un
team, we are the
equipo nosotros somos los
same, but García Monte's firm
mismo pero el bufete de García Monte no
has nothing to do with the
tiene nada que ver con la
one, each one has been with this,
uno cada uno ha sido con esto no se han
they have not set up this roll, no, as far as
montado ellos el rollo este no hasta
I understand, it is balfagón who
donde tengo yo entendido es balfagón la
advises him.  to Rodolfo to hire
que le aconseja a Rodolfo contratar a
Montes as far as I understand eh
Montes hasta donde tengo yo entendido eh
I do believe that they did it without
yo sí creo que lo hayan hecho sin
charging Rodolfo anything I can
cobrarle nada a Rodolfo me lo puedo
believe it because balfagón did a program
creer porque balfagón se hacía programa
in the morning and a program in the afternoon
por la mañana y programa por la tarde
she did but Montes has not done that
ella sí pero Montes no se ha hecho
many programs eh a comment that I have
tantos programas eh un comentario que le
heard Garcia Monten make is that
he escuchado a García monten es como que
he is going But not to resort to Thailand
él va Pero no por recurrir en Tailandia
but now the Superior resources of
sino ahora los recursos Superiores de
the human rights of the UN of I don't know
los derechos humanos de la ONU de no sé
what I don't know how much is there where he
qué no sé cuánto es por ahí por donde él
wants to go eh Where is he insisting on
quiere tirar eh Por donde está empeñando
throwing me like a case in Thailand I
tirar yo cono un caso en Tailandia yo
think it's better that he stayed at home
creo que mejor que se quedado en su casa
and remains as if without opening his mouth because
y se queda como sin abrir la boca porque
every time he opens his mouth really it is
cada vez que abre la boca de verdad es
that it has nothing to do with it he is saying
que no tiene nada que ver está diciendo
things that have nothing to do with it as much
cosas que no tiene nada que ver tanto
as human rights and so many in
como derechos humanos y tantos en
Thailand collaborate with I don't know what it is that
thailandia colaboran con no sé qué es
has nothing to do with it himself that he does
que no tiene nada que ver él mismo que
not focus on what they are saying in what they are
no centra en lo que están diciendo en lo
thinking eh He does not focus on those
que están pensando é No centra esas
things and I think that they are not going to achieve
cosas y yo pienso que no van a conseguir
anything nothing even if they go to court in
nada nada aunque van de tribunal en
Operation they are going to remain the same as
Operación la van a quedar igual como
first instance experience what of
primera instancia experiencia lo que
course not V  to achieve nothing But I
claro que no V a conseguir nada Pero te
tell you that in Europe it is true that
digo que en Europa sí que es verdad que
cases even of terrorism due to
casos incluso de terrorismo por errores
procedural errors or errors like that,
procesales o por fallos así se han
serious condemnatory procedures have been cancelled
cancelado procedimientos serios
eh in Europe but apart
condenatorios eh en Europa pero aparte
from that there is a case in Thailand in
de eso hay un caso en Tailandia en el
which they went and appealed to the Supreme Court with
que fueron y recurrieron al supremo con
a life sentence and the Supreme Court said yes
una cadena perpetua y el supremo dijo sí
no it is raised clear it has raised the
noes elevado claro ha elevado pena de
death penalty I mean so so so
muerte quiero decir que tan tan tan
clear in the sentence so clear and
claro en la sentencia tan clarita y
all in the evidence I mean the
todos en las pruebas O sea que las
evidence so so so overwhelming is that there is
pruebas tan tan tan contundentes es que
nothing changed they can't do anything to
no hay nada cambio ellos no pu nada para
prove what to prove that the
demostrar qué para demostrar que la
police did things wrong or with a
policía ha hecho las cosas mal o en
knife they appeared I don't know how many days they are
cuchillo aparecieron no sé cuántos días
going to laugh at them saying gentlemen
se van a reír de ellos diciendo señores
Take the pill and relax that is what they are
Tómate la pastilla y relájate eso es lo
going to say because what they are thinking is not normal
que van a decir porque no es normal lo
It is that the line of
que está pensando Es que la línea de
defense is so like disastrous and they
defensa es tan como desastrosa y que
are laughing about it the defense even if it
están riendo de ello la defensa aunque
wants words are worth everything no although they
quiera palabras lo valen todo no aunque
want to say that they have done a great
quieran decir que han hecho un gran
job I greatly respect the performance of
trabajo Yo respeto mucho la actuación de
my colleagues as it could not be
mis compañeros como no puede ser de otra
otherwise but they asked for acquittal I
manera pero ellas pedían la absolución
mean Daniel  Sancho had not
es decir que Daniel Sancho no había
committed any crime and they
cometido ningún Crimen y defendían
firmly defended that there had been an
tajantemente que había existido una
unintentional death, a
muerte sin querer un homicidio
reckless homicide, however, we had to
imprudente sin embargo nosotros tuvimos
analyze the evidence produced by the
que analizar las pruebas que realizó la
police and that the prosecution adopted, which
policía y que la fiscalía hizo suyas que
we also did in the
hicimos Nosotros también nuestras en el
oral trial and we defended the premeditation
juici oral y defendimos la premeditación
despite the criticism, the insults, the
pese a las críticas los insultos los
attacks of all those who have come
ataques de todos aquellos que han venido
to defend this
a defender esta teoría de la
conspiracy theory, which I am convinced that they
conspiración que estoy convencido que
can even put in your chat now
inclusive pueden poner ahora en tu chat
that Danil Sancho is innocent. But well,
que danil Sancho es inocente Pero bueno
we were defending the thesis with
veníamos defendiendo las tesis con
caution that we were facing a
prudencia que estábamos ante un
murder with premeditation and that is
asesinato con premeditación Y eso es
precisely what has been proven.
precisamente lo que ha quedado demostrar
So we are very satisfied because
Entonces estamos muy satisfechos porque
our thesis has prevailed,
han prevalecido nuestras tesis el
murder with premeditation, never until
asesinato con premeditación nunca hasta
now had I been reckless in the
la fecha había sido imprudente en el
sense of guessing the verdict. Every time I
sentido de adivinar el fallo siempre que
asked myself what could
me preguntaba que era lo que podía
happen, I with a certain rigor defended that we
suceder yo con cierto rigor defendía que
were facing a murder with
estábamos ante un asesinato con
premeditation but that is going to be
premeditación pero que va a ser lo
difficult to prove in the in the sentence
difícil de probar en el en la sentencia
what would they say when they arrive in Spain what
qué diría ellos han llegar en España qué
is the line of defense going to say that has
es lo que va a decir la línea de defensa
done well, well Mont was
que ha hecho bien bueno Mont ya Mont ya
no longer there  aer there eh if you notice Yes
no estaba aer allí eh si te fijas Sí
but I say that Spain is that they are going to
pero digo cu está España que lo van a
explain it because they always one has been
explicar porque ellos siempre un lleva
here one day and hasn't left you have been
aquí un día y no ha salido llevais un
here one day and he hasn't left no but you know
día aquí no ha salido no pero ya sabes
what he's going to say he's going to say that well
lo que va a decir va a decir que bueno
look they got a
que mira que han conseguido la cadena
life sentence instead of the death penalty and
perpetua en vez de la pena de muerte y
that evidently this is an
que evidentemente que esto es un
absurdity that the prosecutor contradicts himself
despropósito que el fiscal se contradice
with what he said rord a pa est ig to
con lo que dijo rord un pa est ig a
Monte of it doesn't matter Monte comes already with his
Monte de da igual Monte viene ya con su
predetermined thing and starts Talking through
cosa prefijada y empezar Hablar a través
the hard mother of the skull that explodes
de la dura madre del cráneo que explota
outwards and those things and from there you're not
hacia fuera y esas cosas y de ahí no lo
going to
vas
aital and his black or white shirt I don't
aital y su camisa Negra o blanca yo que
know already my mother what an outrage I believe
sé ya madre mía qué barbaridad yo creo
the issue of resources basically to
el tema del recursos básicamente para
prolong its staging in the
alargar su puesta en escena en los
media or rather is that an appeal here what he
medios o sea es que un recurso aquí lo
can get is a
que puede conseguir es una pena de
death penalty but on top of that the first
muerte pero es que encima el primer
appeal if I'm not mistaken you are
recurso si no me equivoco corrígeme tuu
going to review it the same ones who
lo va a revisar los mismos que lo han
condemned him correct it's the same team or
condenado correcto es los mismo equipo o
rather like saying two four and they go saying and
sea como diciendo do cuatro y van dici y
well the same thing but I read one thing
pues lo mismo pero Yo leo una cosa
tuyupa the appeal can go up and down the
tuyupa el recurso puede subir y bajar la
sentence can't just happen
pena no puede pasar cualquier cosa
Exactly go up and down not just down go up
Exacto subir y bajar no solo bajar subir
and down But for it to go up I think
y bajar Pero para que suba Creo que lo
the prosecutor has to ask for it or rather the
tiene que pedir el fiscal o sea el
prosecutor who has to say resources okay
fiscal que tiene que decir recursos vale
But if I go I want
Pero si yo voy yo quiero que se le quite
the commutation to be removed and for it to be the death penalty it has to be the
la conmutación y sea pena de muer tiene
prosecutor juango So this
que ser el fiscal juango Entonces esta
commuted sentence that they talk about
pena conmutada que hablan de pena de
death penalty but commuted to life imprisonment if he
muerte pero conmutada cadena perpetua si
hasn't apologized or anything On what has it been
no ha pedido disculpas ni nada En qué se
based has it been based As I think
ha basado se ha basado Como creo que lo
you yupa said no the
ha dicho tú yupa no la colaboración
initial collaboration with the police has not been based
inicial con la policía no se ha basado
on the work of the defense and it would be
en el trabajo de la defensa y ya estaría
good if one day some media outlet
estaría bien que algún día algún medio
of the more than half the
de comunicación de la más de la mitad
witnesses requested by the defense
los Testigos que solicitó la defensa
for the trial were not admitted none
para el juicio no se admitieron ninguno
more than four Two police officers and two
más que cuatro Dos policías y dos
forensic experts that all the lawyers who
forenses que todos los abogados que
had inus had requested those of
habían inus habían pedido las de la
Carmen herself were not practiced I believe
propia Carmen no se practicaron yo creo
that this whole media storm could have been avoided it would have been
que que se podría haber evitado toda
simpler several months ago to have asked for
sencillo hacía varios meses haber pedido
forgiveness, to have sought to compensate for the damage
Perdón haber buscado resarcir el daño
caused and to have tried to start
producido y haber intentado empezar a
working so that Daniel  could come to
trabajar para que Daniel pudiera venir a
Spain Look, they were very stupid a
España Mira fueron muy tontos un abogado
Thai lawyer would have tried to make a deal and I
tailandés hubiera intentado pactar y te
tell you talking here you talk to lawyers and they
digo hablando aquí hablas con abogados y
tell you they could have gotten a
te dicen se podían haber conseguido una
50 year sentence neither the death penalty nor life
pena de 50 años ni pena de muerte ni
imprisonment they could have
cadena perpetua se podía haber
gotten that why because she had
conseguido eso por qué porque ella había
confessed because she had collaborated with the
confesado porque había colaborado con la
construction because they could have
construcción porque podían haber
compensated the damage by giving money to the
resarcido el daño dando dinero a la
family because she could have asked for forgiveness
familia porque podía haber pedido perdón
and apologies because she could have played the
y disculpas porque podía haber jugado la
psychological card they could have played
baza psicológica podían haber jugado
all that and they didn't want to it's that they didn't want to I mean they
todo eso y no han querido es que no han
could have played the
querido o sea podían haber jugado las
high and low psychological cards Sorry sorry
bazas psicológicas altas y bajas Perdón
sorry give money to the family I
perdón perdón dar dinero a la familia Yo
tell you if I were Rodolfo Sancho
te digo si fuera Rodolfo Sancho dale las
thank him Shake his hand and tell them to
gracias Dale la mano y diles que se
go on television talk about
vayan a las televisiones hablar de
anything get a
cualquier cosa cógete un bufete de
Thai law firm and start working on
abogados tailandés y ponte a trabajar en
your son's pardon for life
el perdón de tu hijo para la cadena
imprisonment and work so that in a few
perpetua y en trabajar en que en unos
years your son can return to a
años tu hijo pueda volver a una cárcel
Spanish prison advice was chosen this
española consejo se optó por esta línea
somewhat aggressive line of defense and in my
de defensa un tanto agresiva y a mi
opinion as a jurist
forma de entender como jurista
implausible of saying that I killed him without
inverosímil de decir que lo maté sin
wanting to by giving him a  punch in the face in
querer dándole un puñetazo en la cara en
the head. As a human being, I neither
la cabeza Yo como como humano tampoco la
share it nor understand it, in addition to all
comparto ni la entiendo además de todo
the discredit and attacks that have been made
el descrédito y ataques que ha habido
against me, therefore, this line
para mi persona por lo tanto esa línea
that has been chosen has increased the pain
que se ha optado ha aumentado el dolor
of Rita's family. I trust and hope that
de la familia Rita confío y espero que
with this sentence from the court, someone will
con esta sentencia del tribunal alguien
once and for all make
de una vez por todas le haga ver a
Daniel Sancho see what he has done, which is to
Daniel Sancho lo que ha hecho que es
kill, murder, dismember, and that this
matar asesinar descuartizar y que eso
is wrong, this is wrong.
está malo eso está malo